Hello friends, welcome to my channel.
Today in this video I will tell you
how we can search on the internet
which is the best health insurance company in India. I will tell you some methods. By
following the tips, you will be able to find out
which health insurance company
is based on the flag that is the greatest. So, today
I will tell you in today's video. So
let's start it. But before
starting, in Display Life, subscribe
my channel and also press the button. So,
friends, to know the best health insurance
company, you will type
Best Health Insurance Company on Google.
See, first remove the option and
click on it. You will see
many options here. We
open these options one by one. Another
option is visible. We also check on it
which company it is showing.
Friends, according to this website which I have opened,
if we check, then it is showing India's
top ten health insurance companies
in 2018. If we see, then it is
showing this life insurance company at the
third position. If we look at Max Bupa Health
Insurance Company, then we are at the third position.  But if we
look at it, it is showing Apollo Health Insurance Company,
but the same thing if I go to
another website and if we
look at the top ten source companies here in Twenty20,
then you will find here that according to this website,
Abir Star Health and Allied
Insurance Company is placed at the setting number of the top company Adidas, so if I
reduce the data of both the websites, then
you will see that one website is
showing Star, and the other website has changed the star code to a few
seconds, here it shows HDFC code at the top,
see from here friends, one
thing we can control from here is that this
website normally
shows you more details so that they
get sponsorship, now let's talk about this Uttarkashi
bride, that is, how was this thing invented, which
health insurance company of India,
for whom, friends, you have to type
IRDA and here object in this
first website which opens, first you should understand the meaning of IRDA,
IRDA means
Insurance Regulatory and Development
Authority, it is not the government which
controls all the insurance companies in India, after this you will
go to the website of the company, click here and
Friends, look at this, friends, it is full
here, you can get all the
information regarding insurance, which the Government of India
releases. Now
what you have to do in subscribing is to know the best health insurance company,
you are looking here, the
option is to subscribe or not, if
you click on this option, you will see that this
detail page will open and here, this Ali Bhai friend,
this is the annual report released by him,
what is the ongoing performance of the health insurance companies running in India, the
IRDA releases its complete report
in detail, you can see the latest 2018-19
report right here, now go to it and
open its Pehli app here, this is the
annual report of IRDA, in this report
you can
check the complete details of every single insurance company present in India,
I will
also share this report with you on its link in the description box, the
information of which I
am sharing with you here, friends,
if you look at this report, here the details of general insurance
companies are given, there are
four companies in the public sector and
in the private sector, here is the total and
compliance, these are the general insurance
companies, private and this  There are some government and
stand-alone health insurance companies in India that have
accounts. These are total scams.
They only sell health products. So,
friends, you need to understand at least once
which can be the best health insurance company for you. To
find out the answer, we will have to check the
company's settlement
ratio. Therefore, I would
say that if you are taking health insurance, then
you should take a company
which only sells health insurance products.
Because if I compare health
insurance with bank loan companies, government
loans and 141 other companies of RBI, then
we will find that the health products of public
sector and private general insurance are
not compatible with this. Normally, they will get very good
incentives or their premiums will be
very high. So, if we look at FD, it would be
best for you to choose a health
insurance company which only
provides you health insurance because
normally there is no third party administrator in these companies.
But if
I talk about  According to the
government and these private sector general insurance companies, till now
it
prevents these incidents from happening that its settlement can happen through
a third party administrator
in your insurance claim settlement,
so this auspicious or inauspicious, first thing from
here we can say that it will be more beneficial for us to choose only
standalone health insurance companies
because it gives
us better offers, patriotic friends, to know the
best health insurance company of India,
we will
go to page number 165 of the annual report of IRDA, here
you can see it written, these are
private sector general and health and
here the complete annual return of private sector general
insurance company and standalone health
insurance company is
given, there are three
columns on it, you can see first net on
medium schools, how much premium did the customer pay in
it, after that there is play in tax, how many
people claimed, after that its ink
bottle embassy, ​​this is
one thing to understand that if we
go to this column of health and here if
we look at the net premium, here
next and previous, the company which has the highest  If it is
more, it somewhere indicates
that the public trusts that company the most.
So, if I look at this chart,
you will see that the
company earning the highest premium is Star Health
& Allied Insurance Company. And see,
friends, I had told you earlier also that
whenever you buy a health insurance company,
try to take a standalone health insurance
company, which can give you better
coverage. Here, the
company registrar who gets the insurance has the highest number of claims,
which means that the public has the highest trust in this
company. Now, if I
look at the record plan in this section,
whatever you will find here, you will
see that the maximum number of people have
claimed for its health special, at
this time this figure
is the highest among the other companies present in the list. And the same thing,
if I talk about the film Race 2,
you will see that for 2018-19, here you
can see which company has the highest call ratio in the list of these standalone companies. The
three companies are Star Health & Allied. Friends,
from this chart you must have understood that the
best health insurance companies of India right now.
This is Star Health and Allied
Insurance Company, so friends, you must have
liked this information of mine and
you should keep watching my videos in the future as well, keep liking
and subscribing, so thank you for
watching my video, thank you.